<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<!-- edited with XMLSPY v2004 rel. 2 U (http://www.xmlspy.com) by lcollins (Firaxis Games) -->
<!-- Sid Meier's Civilization 4 -->
<!-- Copyright Firaxis Games 2005 -->
<!-- -->
<!-- Game Text Strategy -->
<Civ4GameText xmlns="http://www.firaxis.com">
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_RFC_1</Tag>
		<English>To hire a mercenary, click on the "axe" icon in the upper left hand side of the screen.</English>
		<French></French>
		<German></German>
		<Italian></Italian>
		<Spanish></Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_RFC_2</Tag>
		<English>You can check the parameters influencing your stability in the Financial Advisor</English>
		<French></French>
		<German></German>
		<Italian></Italian>
		<Spanish></Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_RFC_3</Tag>
		<English>Not every lake produces 2 food. Some are salt lakes, and thus produce 1 food, like coast.</English>
		<French></French>
		<German></German>
		<Italian></Italian>
		<Spanish></Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_RFC_4</Tag>
		<English>If you get a skull over your cities, it means they have the plague! The population and units in the city and in the surrounding region will probably decrease dramatically. To reduce the effects and the duration of plague, keep your cities healthy.</English>
		<French></French>
		<German></German>
		<Italian></Italian>
		<Spanish></Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_RFC_5</Tag>
		<English>Plague can spread in many ways - through trade routes, along roads and between neighbouring cities.</English>
		<French></French>
		<German></German>
		<Italian></Italian>
		<Spanish></Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_RFC_6</Tag>
		<English>The civilization you choose to play affects your difficulty every bit as much as the difficulty level you choose. Make sure to pick a civ that suits your playing style and your level of expertise.</English>
		<French></French>
		<German></German>
		<Italian></Italian>
		<Spanish></Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_RFC_7</Tag>
		<English>Every civ has hidden modifiers that influence their growth. This way, later civs are not disadvantaged by their late start.</English>
		<French></French>
		<German></German>
		<Italian></Italian>
		<Spanish></Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_RFC_8</Tag>
		<English>You can declare war on independent states only by moving your units into their territory.</English>
		<French></French>
		<German></German>
		<Italian></Italian>
		<Spanish></Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_RFC_9</Tag>
		<English>Combining certain civics will improve or harm the stability of your empire.</English>
		<French></French>
		<German></German>
		<Italian></Italian>
		<Spanish></Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_RFC_XXX</Tag>
		<English>Remember that you can always take control of a newborn civ if you don't like the civilization you started with. You can also use this feature to play from 3000BC even when you want to pick a civ that starts later on.</English>
		<French></French>
		<German></German>
		<Italian></Italian>
		<Spanish></Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_RFC_XXX</Tag>
		<English>In RFC Classical World, vassals can declare war.</English>
		<French></French>
		<German></German>
		<Italian></Italian>
		<Spanish></Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_RFC_10</Tag>
		<English>In RFC Classical World, the max income from a shrine is 20 gold per turn.</English>
		<French></French>
		<German></German>
		<Italian></Italian>
		<Spanish></Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_RFC_11</Tag>
		<English>If you like the mod, and if you have any ideas to improve it, or you just have a bug to report, make sure to check out the development forum at CivFanatics.com.</English>
		<French></French>
		<German></German>
		<Italian></Italian>
		<Spanish></Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_RFC_12</Tag>
		<English>Creating an enormous empire may seem tempting, but you have to be very careful not to let your expansion destabilize your empire! The Empire Civic can help with that.</English>
		<French></French>
		<German></German>
		<Italian></Italian>
		<Spanish></Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_RFC_13</Tag>
		<English>In Rhye's and Fall of Civilization, camera flying mode hotkey has changed to [CTRL + F]</English>
		<French></French>
		<German></German>
		<Italian></Italian>
		<Spanish></Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_RFC_14</Tag>
		<English>If you attempt to stop the growth of newborn civs, some of your units will flip to their side.</English>
		<French></French>
		<German></German>
		<Italian></Italian>
		<Spanish></Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_RFCCW_1</Tag>
		<English>In RFC Classical World, city founding is not allowed in desert or semi-desert if no fresh water is available.</English>
		<French></French>
		<German></German>
		<Italian></Italian>
		<Spanish></Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_RFCCW_2</Tag>
		<English>In RFC Classical World, some exotic mercenaries can only be hired if you have a city in or near their native province.</English>
		<French></French>
		<German></German>
		<Italian></Italian>
		<Spanish></Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_RFCCW_3</Tag>
		<English>In RFC Classical World, the map is divided into historical provinces, which determine AI wars, your stability and historical goals. To see the name of a province, just hover your pointer over a map tile.</English>
		<French></French>
		<German></German>
		<Italian></Italian>
		<Spanish></Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_RFCCW_4</Tag>
		<English>In RFC Classical World, mines are only buildable on resources. Quarries may be built on any hill tile.</English>
		<French></French>
		<German></German>
		<Italian></Italian>
		<Spanish></Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_RFCCW_5</Tag>
		<English>In RFC Classical World, players can claim contested titles, such as the Roman Emperor or the Commander of the Faithful, as one of their victory conditions, or just for the added benefits provided by titles.</English>
		<French></French>
		<German></German>
		<Italian></Italian>
		<Spanish></Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_RFCCW_6</Tag>
		<English>In the RFC Classical World, companies replace corporations. Companies cannot be built - they spread on their own to cities that meet their requirements.</English>
		<French></French>
		<German></German>
		<Italian></Italian>
		<Spanish></Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_RFCCW_7</Tag>
		<English>The Roman civilization has two sets of UHVs, one representing the Republic and one the Empire.</English>
		<French></French>
		<German></German>
		<Italian></Italian>
		<Spanish></Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_RFCCW_8</Tag>
		<English>There are no RFC Embassies, Congresses or the sixth Civic column in RFC Classical World.</English>
		<French></French>
		<German></German>
		<Italian></Italian>
		<Spanish></Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_RFCCW_9</Tag>
		<English>In RFC Classical World, cities two or three tiles away from each other recieve bonus trade routes and Great People points when population thresholds are met.</English>
		<French></French>
		<German></German>
		<Italian></Italian>
		<Spanish></Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_RFCCW_10</Tag>
		<English>Core provinces are most stable and should not fall into enemy hands. Border provinces constitute your historical expansion territory. To see your Core and Border provinces, check your civ's Civilopedia entry, or press [CTRL + K] to toggle the Stability Overlay.</English>
		<French></French>
		<German></German>
		<Italian></Italian>
		<Spanish></Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_RFCCW_11</Tag>
		<English>In order to qualify for "controlling" a province for your historical goals and titles, you need to make sure that all cities in the province are yours, or completely cover it with your culture.</English>
		<French></French>
		<German></German>
		<Italian></Italian>
		<Spanish></Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_RFCCW_12</Tag>
		<English>In RFC Classical World, armies cannot enter another civs territory unless they are at war with them or allies in a common war,  regardless of open borders agreements.</English>
		<French></French>
		<German></German>
		<Italian></Italian>
		<Spanish></Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_RFCCW_13</Tag>
		<English>Building the Summer Palace, Courthouse, State Religion Temple or any National or Great Wonder will increase your Stability.</English>
		<French></French>
		<German></German>
		<Italian></Italian>
		<Spanish></Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_RFCCW_14</Tag>
		<English>During the period covered by this mod, capitals of many empires changed often. Moving your capital in RFC Classical World is cheaper and will not reduce your Stability as badly as in RFC.</English>
		<French></French>
		<German></German>
		<Italian></Italian>
		<Spanish></Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_RFCCW_15</Tag>
		<English>Hold down the [CTRL] key to highlight the province's borders on the map.</English>
		<French></French>
		<German></German>
		<Italian></Italian>
		<Spanish></Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_RFCCW_16</Tag>
		<English>Press [CTRL + K] to toggle the Stability Overlay on/off.</English>
		<French></French>
		<German></German>
		<Italian></Italian>
		<Spanish></Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_RFCCW_17</Tag>
		<English>In RFC Classical World, human players can be vassals of the AI.</English>
		<French></French>
		<German></German>
		<Italian></Italian>
		<Spanish></Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_RFCCW_18</Tag>
		<English>In RFC Classical World, units do not go obsolete when their upgrades are researched.</English>
		<French></French>
		<German></German>
		<Italian></Italian>
		<Spanish></Spanish>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_HINT_RFCCW_19</Tag>
		<English>In RFC Classical World, Deserts, Jungles, Marshs and Forest are impassable unless they are within your borders.</English>
		<French></French>
		<German></German>
		<Italian></Italian>
		<Spanish></Spanish>
	</TEXT>
</Civ4GameText>
